

Europass Curriculum Vitae

Personal information

First name(s) / Surname(s)

Carlo Garatti

Address

Via Matteotti 17, 21015 Lonate Pozzolo (Italy)

Mobile

+393481546008

E-mail(s)

carlo_garatti@yahoo.it

Date of birth

06 June 1976

Gender

Male

Desired employment / Occupational field

I'm interested in building architectures built around new technologies, OOP paradigms in an agile prospective. Always on the path to research the core of TDD and the real meaning of objects. In the last two years i'm searching a method to remove complexity. I use PomodoreTecnique as a task managment method.

Work experience

Dates

2010 →

Occupation or position held

Developer

Main activities and responsibilities

Name and address of employer

Mediolanum

Type of business or sector

Dates 2009 - 2010

Occupation or position held

Software engineer @Oracle

Main activities and responsibilities

Application written in Java to integrate modules between eBS and UCM using XP.

Entrepreneur to introduce XP @Oracle Italy

Technologies: JAVA, XML

Name and address of employer

Siram

Type of business or sector

PA Services

Dates

2008 - 2008

Occupation or position held

Software engineer @Oracle

Main activities and responsibilities

Develop custom web apps to supprt CRM processes for the main telco provider in Norwey (Telia

Sonera)

Technologies: JAVA, XML, JEE

Dates

2007 - 2008

Occupation or position held

Software engineer @Oracle

Main activities and responsibilities

Integration between Oracle E-business Suite and Oracle Transportation Manager with Oracle Soa

Suite (BPEL and ESB)

Technologies: BPEL. ESB. JAVA

Name and address of employer

Italsempione Vittuone

Page 1 / 3 - Curriculum vitae of Carlo Garatti

For more information on Europass go to http://europass.cedefop.europa.eu

© European Union, 2002-2010 24082010

Type of business or sector Logistics

> **Dates** 2007 - 2007

Occupation or position held Developer @ Oracle Italia

Main activities and responsibilities Developing a web - based portal for HR department with Oracle E-business Suite

Technologies: JAVA, XML, ADF

Name and address of employer

Type of business or sector

2006 - 2006 **Dates**

Barilla

Occupation or position held Developer @ Oracle Italia

Main activities and responsibilities Developing custom reports with Oracle XML Publisher Tool

Technologies: JAVA, XSLT-FO

Name and address of employer MINIMOTOR SA - Croglio

Type of business or sector

2005 - 2006 Dates

Occupation or position held Junior Developer @ Oracle Italia

Main activities and responsibilities Developing web - based customs for Crm products in Oracle E-business Suite

Technologies: JAVA, XML, J2EE

Name and address of employer

Type of business or sector

Fiera Milano Spa - Rho

2004 - 2005 **Dates**

Occupation or position held Developer @ HRC Milano

Main activities and responsibilities Database refactoring and developing PL/SQL procedures.

Portale hr appraisal (C#)

Technologies: C#, XML

Name and address of employer

Wind - Milano

Type of business or sector Telco

Education and training

1996 - 2003 **Dates**

Title of qualification awarded University Degree (Laurea)

Principal subjects / occupational skills Computer Science

Name and type of organisation Politecnico Milano (Politecnico Milano)

providing education and training

Dates 1990 - 1995

Title of qualification awarded Perito Elettronico

Name and type of organisation Istituto Tecnico Statale, Gallarate (Istituto Tecnico Statale, Gallarate) providing education and training

Personal skills and competences

> Mother tongue(s) Italian

Page 2 / 3 - Curriculum vitae of For more information on Europass go to http://europass.cedefop.europa.eu Carlo Garatti © European Union, 2002-2010 24082010

Other language(s)

Self-assessment European level (*)

English

Understanding				Speaking				Writing	
	Listening	Reading		Spoken interaction		Spoken production			
B2	Independent user	C1	Proficient user	В1	Independent user	B2	Independent user	B1	Independent user
/±\	_	_			SEE) 1 1		-		-

(*) Common European Framework of Reference (CEF) level

Technical skills and competences

OPERATING SYSTEMS:UNIX, LINUX (Ubuntu)
PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES: JAVA, Ruby

MARKUP LANGUAGES: XML, XSL-T, XPATH, HTML, XHTML

DATABASES: ORACLE

APPLICATION SERVER: Oracle Application Server, Weblogic

FRAMEWORK: OAF (Java & XML), SPRING, XML Publisher (print formatter driven by XSL formatting

objects (XSL-FO)), ADF, EclipseLink, JQuery

TOOLS: Jdeveloper, Eclipse, Ant, Git

Oracle SOA Stack (Soa Suite, Oracle Service Bus)

Object Oriented Analysis, Design principles and Solid Design

Computer skills and competences

Trying to be Agile

TDD: red-green-refactor cycle, spike, acceptance tests.

Trying to create Object Oriented Software, following the lessons learned by Francesco Cirillo and his

Workshop of Emerging Design.

Trying to create malleable software.

Trying to work in an Agile Team.

Driving licence(s)

В

Additional information

In the last year i'm attempting to introduce Agile in Oracle Italy SOA 's lob, using XP and TDD metodologies following Agile Manifesto.

Have held courses on OAF and XML Publisher and XML related tecnologies for Oracle Partners and employees

Introducing new tecnologies into Oracle's italy apps-tech lob.

I'd like to be an active member in Open Source Community.

Annexes

For Italy only: Autorizzo al trattamento dei dati personali come da D. L. 196/2003.

Twitter: http://twitter.com/cgaratt

GitHub: https://github.com/carlino

Member of: jugmilano, milano-xpug, milano-codingdojo